<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luru</title>
    <description>My name is Luis Ruiz. I'm a Technical Lead Developer at Plain Concepts, author and speaker based in Madrid, Spain.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 10:15:40 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 10:15:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting a blog for my future self</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Luis Ruiz. I’m a Technical Lead Developer at Plain Concepts, author and speaker based in Madrid, Spain. I never really thought that I would start a blog in english, but I decided to start for two main reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, to remember to my future self things that I’ve done before and I don’t want you to waste time looking for a solution and also help people with similar problems sharing my experiencies. Of course, I’m glad to learn from you and your comments are welcome!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Second, to improve my english through this blog trying to write a lot of post and also reach to more people through this language. It’s a fact that English is the main language where you can find a lot information and one of my challengues is to attend an international conference as speaker, so I’m trying to achieve it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you going to find in this blog?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m focused principally in Microsoft Technologies such us C#, ASP.NET Core, Azure, Azure DevOps… so most of the content will be related with these topics but I never close the door on write about other techonologies. I’ll try to share with you real problems in my daily work life, so I hope you find it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy blogging!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/starting-a-blog-for-my-future-self</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/starting-a-blog-for-my-future-self</guid>
        
        <category>Career</category>
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
        <category>Self</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
